Let's dive in.
>> Junkyard Love podcast. At what age do we
learn how to have better conversation?
>> Jumpyard Love podcast
>> 5 4 3 2
>> Um well welcome Christine. Thank you for
your time. Um I would like to start with
kind of the elevator pitch. I was just
saying you have so much interesting in
your in your uh background in your work
in your history of things to teach and
share about. Um what's the elevator
pitch? Say we just bumped into each
other. It's a long elevator ride. It's
it's a you know 100 plus floors. And I
say hey what what do you do? What are
you into Christine? What would your
answer to that be?
>> Well some of it I pick from where you
are at you know junkyard love right. So
the power of that um as both an
emotional which I call a vital body um
solution and a spiritual or quantum body
solution. So that's you know we can go a
couple directions there [clears throat]
>> but love is an answer. It's a solution
for sure.
>> Okay. And you you study love you study I
mean you already mentioned quantum
>> study the four bodies. So a ebook I have
available for people is four bodies four
medicines. And so when you talk about
the heart, you know, on a physical
level, the heart obviously there's
medicine, right? I'm not a cardiologist,
so I'm not giving any of that advice
today, but I do have a degree in natural
medicine and understand that if stuff's
showing up on your in your physical
body, it typically has to do with what's
going through your vital body, your
mental body, and your quantum body. So,
those are the the other bodies in the
four body model.
So there's there's a summary of where we
could go.
>> Okay. [laughter]
>> This discussion.
>> Okay. I definitely want to explore more
of the specifically quantum. But I think
even just starting out with, you know,
seeing our bodies and who we are on four
different levels, four different planes.
>> So, so how is that important? You know,
normally we go to the doctor and they
see us, they check out the physical
level, like they look, what what do we
see? What do our um tests give us?
What's the data? Um, what are the more
expansive ways of understanding
ourselves,
>> our body?
>> Well, so I just I did another podcast
where we talked about, you know, some
people question anything that's not
physical, like like give me the
evidence, you know, like how do I know
that there's this thing called spirit or
you know that there's an essence to your
um like you've got chakras or you've
got, you know, something that you can't
see. And you know, there's the the
analogy of the wind. So, you know, we're
talking about the weather. Well, how do
you see the, you know, can you see the
wind?
Like, if you look outside, can you see
wind coming by? No, you can see the
effects of the wind. So, you'll look to
see, are the trees blowing? Is there
paper coming up from the ground? Is
that, you know, are the clouds going
faster than normal? You know, so you see
the effects of the wind. And that's the
same thing as So, the wind is basically
the physical body. Well, sorry. The wind
is actually the spirit. The effects are
the physical body. So, so we see the
effects of that, you know, in our body
from what has been going on, the
invisible level,
>> right? And Okay. And so, these are a
couple of the levels that you understand
the physical body. Let's back up to even
more of how you even got to
understanding these things. Um, did you
have a history? I mean, I mean, I know
this, but my listeners may not. Can we
talk a little bit about a little bit
about your history of kind of
understanding your own body and diving
more into these things?
>> Well, yeah. So, I had a chemical
imbalance growing up and you know that
showed up for me as chronic depression,
like almost incapacitating anxiety. Um,
I barely got to school in junior high.
you know, I had so much anxiety, peer
pressure, things that were just like
beyond, you know, I didn't even talk
about because I was, you know, so
blocked in my ability to process and get
through that. And so, I actually turned
to substances. By the time I was in high
school, I had just basically kind of
thrown my hands in the air like, I just
don't think I'm ever going to get better
using what I know. And so I went to
unknowns and to you know even nos to to
try to self-medicate. Um so I found that
it did change my brain to you know
certain and I went on this quest to find
the substance that you know
did had the impact I was looking for.
And and for me, you know, I now I that
was my first career is substance abuse
um counseling. And I can tell you how
often people are self-medicating without
even realizing they're self-medicating.
They just want to feel better. They just
they want energy. If they're tired,
they're they want to feel happy. If
they've, you know, they live in this
dense, heavy depression, they're looking
to function. if anxiety is getting in
the way of basic life,
you know. So, so that's typically why
people get into something that's
physically changing them. So that was my
first experience with understanding the
physical and and so I wrote the book 10
ways to balance your brain chemistry
after I you know my whole life was
transformed and I realized that the
chemical imbalance didn't all go away
even though the substances were not the
solution anymore. I still had chronic
depression. I still had anxiety, bouts
of anxiety. So I discovered natural ways
to resolve it, higher frequency ways to
resolve those chemical imbalances. So
that's what I talk about in the physical
body as you know, you can you can alter
your physical well-being through a lot
of different things. And if you go a
natural route, you're more likely to
have better longer term solutions
without side effects or other, you know,
consequences. Right.
>> Right.
So there's the start.
>> Okay. What what what did you discover um
in in your long paths of dealing with
substance abuse and helping other people
and obviously even with your own
journey. Um you know and you continued
to going you continued to keep going and
exploring more and learning more about
just the human body and the human mind
and everything after that. um now now
that it's been so long between you know
your your years of being just a
substance abuse counselor and the things
you were doing with that what would you
say that you learned um in big part that
>> well that's where I started you know so
like if you break down the chemistry and
let's talk about endorphins because your
show is about love so it's tricky to
look at how to correct endorphins so
serotonin is one that we talk about a
lot more so we understand you know
serotonin is is a physical condition.
You know, it's a chemical. It's a um it
gives you a sense of well-being and you
can get serotonin from
your food, your diet. So, carbs, you
know, when people get into comfort
foods, you know, um there's a book
called Potatoes Not Prozac. That says a
lot in the title,
>> right? So, I studied that. That was one
of the first kind of primers that was a,
you know, a launch pad for 10 ways. And
and so I was figuring out like what I'm
eating matters and the carbs I was going
to were actually causing my depression
because I had a wheat and wheat
sensitivity, which we see a lot more
now. So this was in the 90s when I was
figuring out my brain chemistry. We
weren't talking about gluten-free then.
But it made a huge difference for me to
change my diet and but how would I know
that right? So that had to be kind of
informed through a higher source and I
was also on a spiritual journey at the
time. And so what I found is that I can
actually be led to solutions in my
physical well-being through
like a higher source, you know, a truth
that if I aware and open to it, you
know, can come through. And so that was
important. So that's the serotonin side.
What I figured out also in this journey
is that it wasn't really the serotonin
that was out of balance for me. It was
the endorphins. And it also talks about
that in potatoes not Prozac. It's, you
know, explains that the serotonin is
influenced by carbs and, you know,
comfort foods, but the endorphins are
influenced. I'm going to see if you can
guess
that. And it stands for inner orphine,
which is like morphine, right?
Endorphin.
So, this is like your um pain receptors
and feelgood chemistry, but highly
addictive, you know, like narcotics.
Can you do you know the foods food group
that fits with this? It's not really a
group.
>> Oh, like alcohol.
>> Close. Alcohol affects GABA levels.
Okay.
>> Sugar.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> On the continuum of narcotics, sugar's
actually on that continuum. It's a
It's a narcotic.
>> Isn't that interesting? And so I that
made so much sense to me to understand
that I was addicted to sugar as a kid,
you know, and it's just one of those
like so many people try to get off of it
and you go through like serious
withdrawals. Isn't that wild? Think.
Yeah.
>> Mhm. So, so that was that's been a
battle for me is to to be the master of
my endorphin, you know, pathways and and
not let sugar take over or cravings,
that type of thing.
>> And
so, so you went through this journey of
discovering like what different
substances even are. So, it wasn't just
like alcohol or drugs or whatever. you
you discovered even just addictions to
food, addictions to did did it expand
into more like, you know, understanding
addictions to patterns or even like our
relationships with one another? Um, I
think I've kind of me heard you mention
things like this on podcast.
>> Yeah. So, there's two areas I think are
important to look at here. So, one is
dopamine is a very different chemical
than endorphins and they're both highly
addictive. So, dopamine is more charged.
It's like when I was going through some
phases. So, my drug of choice was
cocaine. So, cocaine definitely fits in
that dopamine category because it's it's
like it numbs and creates that um like
you can't sustain dopamine like you
can't be high at that level all the
time. It will actually turn into
psychosis if you try.
>> Yeah. And you know it's but those
charges those big bursts are so you know
like we go after them some of us right
um gambling is one of those that will
you know obviously you can't be gambling
all the time right that will be a
problem um so that's tricky and but it
helped me to understand I was bipolar so
there was a diagnosis I got at some at
one point in there that was for bipolar
disorder and I had to become the master
my dopamine as well because I realized
if I come up I will go down. And the
trick was not to try to change it and
stay up. The trick was to realize when I
was down there was some there was some
work to do. There was some healing to do
and to not just try to get back up but
allow myself to find that natural middle
path so to speak in living. So that's
that was a big lesson in life. But the
other one is with that endorphins um
that's where the love addict comes in.
So, so the you know sugar is the
chemical or the physical I guess fix
with endorphins but on the emotional
level it's typically we're seeking love
and that for a lot of us is romantic
love or some kind of sense of like
belonging or
um security from you know that it's like
a warm fuzzy kind of thing and and it's
not necessarily wrong.
>> So, one of the things I found in this
whole process is, you know, I call it
the spiral. So, the the spiral includes
things that you want to do abstinence
with on the outside,
>> which heroin probably not a good idea on
the endorphin, you know, continuum.
Probably going to let that go. Going to
do abstinence from that one. But the
next layer of that
>> spiral that goes inner inward is
moderation. And so what I discovered is
I had to find a way to do moderation
with
this relationship or romantic
craving
and you know you get into the honeymoon
you know and you want to stay there and
then you know it fluctuates. And so um
so some of that is moving past the
addictive nature of love and into the
third part of the cycle which is
attainment.
And attainment is doing the work to have
longer term real solutions. And so in a
relationship, right, it's not just, oh,
we love the honeymoon and then it gets
hard. And so, do we stay or do we go?
You know, so with the attainment part,
that's, you know, it closes that gap,
that inner hole, which is really what
we're trying to fill to a solution
that's more solid, like a deeper love, a
more complete type of sense of self
could be self- loveve.
Right.
>> So you start getting into that center
with that.
>> So So what are the with these cycles
with these four steps? What are we
trying to complete with these cycles
ideally? Like what is it that we're
trying to get?
>> Isn't that a good question? Yes. So it h
it is a healing an inner healing.
And so I actually developed this spiral
model when I was working in a in a jail.
So I I took my recovery and you know
started creating a curriculum with it
with some these concepts as a substance
abuse counselor and I was teaching this
I was creating this actually as I was
working with inmates and I had some of
them tell me that you know they had even
done this attainment thing like they
talked to me about like you know we we
did 12 years you know sober um doing the
AA thing and you know some of the
attainment things are are, you know,
self-help programs or religious
commitments or health and wellness
commitments, you know, things that are
like, oh, you're probably not going to
get addicted to going to the gym, you
know, but you want to attain something
through that, you know, or education,
you know, they you go get a degree and
they were doing all these things, right,
and they still relapsed. And so I took
it as like this is a challenge like I
had actually 20 years clean by the time
I was teaching this. So I felt pretty
stable but there were areas of my life
like relationships that I had not
figured out. Like I kept getting into
unhealthy relationships. So I knew that
if I were to complete you know if I were
to figure this out um that was the
challenge right? So, so I'd gone the
through the attainment model myself and
I remember there was a night I left the
jail and I my boyfriend broke up with me
as I was driving home. It was a Friday
night like going home alone on a Friday
night,
right? [laughter]
So, what's interesting is I was on this
spiritual journey. I was studying Cabala
and it happened to be
the moment of Yamapur. So Yam Kapur in
the in the Jewish tradition, you know,
starts at sundown and it's a it's a a 24
hours
um they call it the day of atonement.
And if you look at that word atonement,
it's at onement.
It's a
a devotion
after Rashashana. So you've done 10 days
of deep diving, you know, excavating
your past here and where you could
improve and what it means amends you may
have to make or changes in your life and
and this 24 hours, you know, typically
people dress in white, they fast and
they don't work or, you know, maybe
engage in regular life stuff and they
just spend that 24 hours in like divine
connection.
And I got home and realized like, okay,
well, I guess I don't know what this
means, but I choose this. And I remember
I was lying on my couch and the sun came
down. I mean, it's like Yamapur starts
at sundown. And I remember there was
this light that's almost like it entered
like a shaft through the top of my head
and it poured through it felt like my
spine.
From head to toe I felt light
enter me
and that was the solution. So the
solution of this spiral is at this
center
really all that matters is that you are
whole and complete through a divine
connection
and you bring your whole self to it.
Yeah.
>> Okay. Can can I ask I'm I'm not sure
what language you typically use for this
now. Do you call this a condundalini
awakening? Um obviously spiritual
awakening is probably a terminology
you've used but do you have you do into
condundalini?
>> I have. I love kundalini.
>> Yeah. Did you consider that an awakening
in itself or was that just another
Kundalini related experience or
>> Kundalini was very supportive of you
know there was a phase in my life where
um my healing journey was very much
influenced by it and
my experience with that though is that
the condalini was more about making
corrections in my vital body. So the
vital body contains the chakras,
meridians and your arc fields. And
that's a layer of us that is very much
neglected by western medicine, you know,
but important in influencing the
physical self and connected to the
quantum self. So yeah, so that's where I
would place Kundalini in that very
effective vital body tool and you know
process to
to clear and and strengthen the vital
body.
>> Yeah.
>> Sure.
>> Okay. So when you had um when you had
your first kind of initial awakening,
would you say I mean I mean have you I
I'm not sure if I asked you. Have you
always had some sort of spiritual side
to you? would you say were did you grow
up um you know in a religion? Were you
always spiritual or was this kind of a
later in life awaken?
>> That's a great question. Okay. So, I
grew up in a religion uh Christian-based
and I followed as much as I could with
it but like I you know like I just
shared my
chemistry was not working [laughter]
and religion didn't fix it. So, so I
left religion in my, you know, path with
substance use. And but here's what's
kind of cool. So, and I'm I'm going to
release my recovery story. So, I don't
want to give it all away because um
that's going to come out. So, it's
called Yearning for Freedom. And so in
my early, you know, late teens and early
young adult life, I just wanted freedom
from the guilt
because that is one of the things that
happens with someone who's, you know,
got a religious influence and, you know,
is fighting against it or steering away
from it. And so,
so I wanted freedom from guilt, but I
also wanted freedom from pain and
suffering.
>> And, you know, I just thought if I just
find this, it's got to be out there. You
know, I was looking definitely outside
myself, but not only outside myself, but
down, you know, frequency wise. It was
like I was not looking up, right? And so
I found cocaine.
It was a great solution for a few months
and then it started taking a toll on me,
I would say. And there was a moment when
you talk about spiritual things, I think
it's important to look at the dark as
well as the light. So there was a moment
when I had used this drug for, you know,
several like eight months or so and
still could kind of take it, leave it,
you know, it's like I could still do
life and then wait for the weekend or
whatever.
But there was a there was a night I
remember very specifically where I was,
you know, with a couple people and we
were using and a friend came to the
door. So, this friend had been bubbly,
energetic. She did not have depression
like I dealt with. Um, until she open we
opened the door that night and her whole
demeanor was different. Her vibration
was different. And even then, I could
sense like what happened, you know? And
she'd come back from a funeral from a
friend of hers who had overdosed
and and she just couldn't shake it.
And was it an it? Because she came over
and joined the party. And I remember
that like almost in an instant I gone
from the freedom I had with this drug to
being controlled by it.
So theoretically, and this is just me
from, you know, a perspective looking
back at that, I believe that the person
who overdosed came with her and walked
through the door. Okay. So this entity
earthbound essence
[snorts] like
attached to me. And so it was like I
after that point in time I couldn't say
no. I didn't have like power over what I
was what was going on. I started losing
weight. I started experiencing all the
you know late stage
consequences of my use.
So that's my theory. People may or may
not you know get that. There's actually
a book that came out that that it you
know would coincide with this called uh
Return from Tomorrow. Richie is the name
of the the first or last name of the
author. And he talks about his
near-death experience where he was
moving in and out. You know, you hear
about people who have, you know, who are
an operating table or whatever, but
they're also experiencing other things
through in spirit form. and he stepped
into a bar and watched as people were
sitting around the bar, but there were
also earthbounds senior bar with them
waiting for them to drink to a certain
point and then it was like they kind of
unzipped them and entered to vicariously
continue, you know, to have that
>> experience. Isn't that interesting?
>> That's a very interesting way to look at
it. It I feel like it coincides with my
experience as well. I mean, back in in
my in my days of drinking and partying
and and nights of cocaine and that sorts
of thing,
>> I feel like um
>> yeah, that's a very interesting way way
to look at it. So, what do what do you
think that is? I mean, do you see that
do you see that as a a positive way or
positive perspective of addressing these
things that people are dealing with?
Like, how can you spot it? like if
someone comes to you nowadays and um you
know maybe they have one of these
entities that's kind of hanging over
them and maybe um I mean what's your
approach if you do deem that's the case
how can we shake off these entities so
to say
>> so this is actually where we start
talking quantum things and so in quantum
university they actually refer to this
as perverse energy
>> and so you're working at the spiritual
level with the healing process um
sometimes it's generational so I've had
clients who have it's like they they're
they're affected by something that's
always been there and as we tune into
that and I just I use a lot of intuition
with this like sometimes I'll just know
like it's you know like it's an ancestor
like a you know great-grandfather
whatever and or grandmother and you know
and I'll say certain things and they'll
be like oh yeah I've heard that like my
my mom's mom had depression or whatever
right and so and so sometimes I'll I'm
actually doing therapy on both. You
know, we invite them to stay and and
experiencing the healing.
>> So that's quantum stuff. And kundalini
is really interesting when you say that.
My first condundalini session when I
went to a you know a it was actually
geared towards addiction released. So
the the series the kundalini series I
went to was done by a a gentleman who
was using it for addiction recovery as
well. And I remember starting the
process and you know doing the tuning in
and different things and I experienced
my grandfather like I'm like wow you
know
>> and what I did in that condalini se
session actually cleared something for
him. He had um you know he'd passed away
with a lot of heavy emotion like he'd
you know we knew like he wasn't well
when he left so it it cleared it. It was
amazing.
>> So that's one approach. I do other
energy healing type techniques with
clients and so but there are ways. So
when you're working with the vital body
um there's a it's like a bridge between
the physical body and the quantum body
want to call it that. So that's that's
important. It's a it's denser than the
quantum but you know it's higher you
know it's a other dimensional than the
physical
>> and it's and it's and you have success
being I mean obviously it's very
intuition based but is there like series
of um you know other more uh commonly
known psychological techniques you know
like I've heard you talk about tapping
and EMDR and these sorts of things so do
you kind of use uh various different
types of psychological treatments to
kind of feed into your intuition of what
needs to happen next or
>> Yes you mentioned okay so EFT is the
tapping technique emotional freedom
technique I started training in at in
2002 2003. So it was when Gary Craig was
actually doing his program and I went
through all of his basic and all of his
advanced. I loved it and um I actually
was in a career at the time where I
couldn't use it and it inspired me or
motivated me to get into private
practice so I could have the freedom to
use it with clients. So as I was using
that, I started developing very unique
kind of adaptations with it enough and
then with my training with quantum
university I brought in a whole you know
like accessing the zero white field and
doing things to clear at the quantum
level. So it became zero point gradient
is what you know it now is called DPM
and and so yes I've absolutely used
that. So um like in the case where I
described you know a woman comes to my
ops and figure out that she's like
carrying something that's not even just
hers when we're doing it's DPM that
where I will actually do with the client
and even that other you know
being that may be influenced because it
can actually cross over especially when
there's like a generational connection
>> um I find that it could clear mult
multi-level clearing
and and I do have used that in place of
EMDR. did get certified in EMDR but um
the research I've done this ZPM is
actually twice as effective in relieving
physical emotion and on the four bodies
you know twice as effective as the MTR
in associ
>> so yeah it's it's good stuff
>> that that's awesome okay I I want to um
I want to add just just one more time
back on this like entities thing where I
think it's always a very interesting
thing to explore kind of what what
thoughts are not my own? What are kind
of old patterns that like are ways of
thinking that don't serve me? You know,
what what is my intuition versus what is
um you know maybe a negative thought
pattern or a negative entity or
something that's not me and that's you
know I don't necessarily have to um
solve or you know get in the ring in the
boxing gloves with necessarily but I can
kind of treat it as separate than me. Um
can you can you help me like explore
anybody listening how do we delineate
these things? How do we separate like
what's us and our intuition? First step
in writing is the mental body.
>> Yeah.
>> So the mental body, this is so
interesting and and I hope people will
grab the four bodies for medicine ebook
to really explore this too. But the
example I use in there is, you know,
it's it's like we're trying to if we try
to use the mind to correct the mind, we
can get just a lot of chaos going on,
right? And so, um, so it's actually
trying to go back and forth between
positive thinking, negative thinking.
You know, it's like, oh, there I am
doing negative thinking. Then the judge
comes in. It's like, you should be
negative thinking. So, we have that
voice. We're like, oh, you better be
positive thinking. We have that voice.
Just a lot of chaos, right?
So, the solution I found for that is it
goes back to zero.
So, it's actually neutrality.
So neutrality
had the the option of not charging your
thoughts with anything. Um so I like
playing the neutral game. Do you want to
play the neutral game with me?
>> Let's go.
>> Okay. So the neutral game is a way to
bring the mind to the present moment and
with zero emotion just neutral state
present moment. So, so if I'm playing a
game in my setting right here, I'm going
to say, okay, there is a clock in front
of me, you know, I can give the time. I
can look around and see there's, you
know, there's four frames on my wall.
Um, my chair is black
and and then I can go into kind of s
like auditory senses. So, I hear some
white noise.
And I might see something out the
window,
but it's it's like you're bringing
yourself back to, oh, I can feel. So, if
I put my toes on the ground, I can feel
my chair protector, you know?
Um, I can feel the texture of
my chair.
And and so you can see it's kind of like
you have to slow down to be able to
identify
the the experience and you avoid, you
know, like qualifiers or adjectives that
add emotion to it. The goal is to just
be
like there are
four drawers.
The water bottle is blue.
I smell. You could do a smell. You have
smell.
Interesting. So, can you see yourself
doing that in your room?
>> But [clears throat]
you can do it when you're driving. M
>> because a lot of times we I know when I
was driving I had a commute for a while
and oh I go into some head stop
>> and and so just practicing this you know
sky is blue there's a white car in front
of me
turn off the radio you know and just be
in the silence.
Yeah.
>> And and it and the trick is you're
actually changing your neuropathways
with it, like a mindfulness exercise
basically.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I I think um I think it helps
people really kind of notice cuz when
you really kind of start to stack on a
few of these different sense techniques,
you know, you actually do realize that
you've been smelling this whole time,
but you didn't really notice and you
have the taste of, you know, you just
brushed your teeth or you have the taste
of coffee, you have the taste of
whatever in your mouth. Um and then like
you said, you're pointing at things or
you're naming things and either saying
them out loud or just at least just
identifying them. I think what happens
is a lot of people suddenly kind of are
pulled out of to the they're pulled out
of their thought loops. You know, they
didn't realize so much that they had
just been in this world of only
thinking. And um it's it's it's funny
because thinking is a sense. We know
that. And it's called a sense just like
smelling and just like seeing and
whatever. But I think we give it so
much, you know, uh we give it so much
power. It's like the ultimate always
thinking sense. It's it's where we think
everything needs to belong. And so we
get stuck kind of in thinking and we end
up to some extent we kind of ignore the
other senses. And I think um that's
where the the thought loops and kind of
like the old patterns can take place
when we're stuck in just the thinking
mode.
Yeah. So mindfulness is a way in to the
present moment and and so it took me a
while to get to meditation as a practice
of stillness and silence. And so for me,
my mind was so busy. Um, the first thing
I got to do was yoga. And so I had and
it was so divinely like I knew it was
God because it was I would house someone
and it's so sad it took me so long, but
I I had to be with people for almost a
year to get it. So I was actually
supporting a woman in um recovery and I
would you know support her with
principles and then she would tell me oh
you should go do yoga and she would ask
me every week have you done yoga and by
the time like we worked together for
several months I was like I have to go
do yoga so I can at least answer yes. So
I got the book by Baron Baptiste um
Journey to Power and that's how I
started. I didn't go to a yoga studio. I
just started at home and but I reading
his book it was like I was compelled I
was like oh this is a solution and he
talked about the gap between stimulus
and response. I remember that. And
basically he's talking about the power
we have to change our neuropathways
with a pause and that when you use your
body as part of that process, it's so
like there's something to it that you
can't just do with your mind. So if it's
definitely the mind body connection
where
it's like critical for me, I do not go a
week without yoga. I probably could do
it more often, but I at least get there.
And I do go to studios now, you know,
and I like the slower pace
>> because it creates that gap between
stimulus and response. It's like it
creates that opportunity
for me to be present in the moment to
make a different choice
>> and slow down. And so so yeah, yoga is
definitely a solution for the mind
um without involving the mind, without
creating the chaos.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And yeah, yoga is is so
satisfying on every single level. It's
it's so such an enjoyable thing. I mean,
even even just doing 20 minutes of yoga
from YouTube a day or you do like a Zoom
class or something. I mean, it it it's
so nice. the um I think that the breath
work aspect of yoga as well like it it
forces you to breathe in ways that if if
you weren't doing yoga you likely
probably wouldn't be breathing in those
ways and I think that's ultimately you
know massively helpful for for us as
well. It was certainly part of my
journey was was yoga as well and uh the
breath work side of things and learning
how to kind of be at one with my
movements and breath and things like
that would put me in these just
delightful states you know really really
help helped a ton. Um, Christine, I I I
have to ask you. Um, this might be a
shelf a selfish offtrail, but I've
mentioned that you uh have gotten into
transcendental meditation as well.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Um, I I love TM. It's um I I like
meditation just generally as well, but
you know, my daily practice is still the
the 20 minutes uh the mantra. I I still
just love that one. You do it?
>> Yeah, I still I still do it. So, I want
to ask about um your experience. So
maybe assuming that a listener hasn't
really even heard of TM, can I just kind
of hear a little bit about your journey
with transcendental meditation?
>> Yes, for sure. So, okay. So, I'm going
to tell you about my whole journey of
meditation though.
>> Excellent.
>> So, so here's where I started. So, I did
my yoga, got that down, and then I knew
that I was meant to explore Eastern
meditation. So my first um glimpse at
that was actually a movie called doing
time doing vaposa.
So and I don't know how I came across
it. I just it was like okay real
meditation looks like vaposa. So if you
know anything about that that requires
10 days of silence and we actually there
is a the pasta retreat you know within
you know a distance from me that I could
have done it and I and but my I was like
I don't know how I do that and so in the
movie or the documentary it shows how
the apostina changed the nature of a a
prison one of the worst prisons in the
world in India. So they which of course
it kind of makes sense that you know
you'd see more of a pass in India but
the um anyhow I guess apparently they
weren't all practiced in it and so they
brought it into the prison and it
transformed the inmates to where it
reduced the general issues. Um they
created better dynamics with them at the
guards. It was like really
transformative. So I thought that was so
interesting. So I I'm doing a I did a a
teaching of you know I was teaching
about principles around Easter
meditation and I did this on 11 1111. So
I I I did something and it was at 11:00
a.m. Okay. So I'm all about the numbers.
So, so November 11th, 2011, I opened
this door in a big way and and I
understand the 11s are about doors and
all kinds of cool stuff, but but I went
on record saying um I hope I do not have
to go to prison to learn how to
meditate.
So, it felt like a prison concept to me
like I couldn't imagine 10 days of
silence unless I was like there was
nothing else to do. So, so I'll go from
there to um later I encountered a former
Buddhist monk who who sat with me and I
had not been able to get into silence
and stillness. So he worked with me and
and in this work with me he taught me
mahasi which mahosity meditation is a
movement based meditation. So it's like
a transition between yoga and
meditation. So you can do it sitting you
know that it involves some arm and leg
patterning and um and so I was working
with that and then we started talking
about my deepest fears. So I had this
fear as I worked with him that if I were
completely silent and still that it
wasn't safe. Okay. So it was kind of
like it would mean I'm and I actually
could associate it with non-existence
and somehow I had this fear that my
deepest fear was I would cease to exist
and the more still and silent I was
where I feel like I fell into that fear.
So the doings and the active motion was
like a survival mechanism for me. My
subconscious felt like I was alive and I
existed as long as I was doing.
being wasn't as safe because it it at
the some level I you know it has to do
with that emptiness as in me or
something. It was like I would fall into
the black hole of nothingness.
So I worked with him on that fear for a
while and and through that I was able to
um grasp zero. So when we talk about
that neutrality,
there is something beyond that on a
quantum level that is actually the zero
point field where all energy is removed
from my system. It is actually a ceasing
of all. Okay. So this thing that I was
so afraid of, I actually had to move
through it.
And in moving through it,
I found and some of this was through
quantum entrainment. Dr. Frank Kensow is
an advocate of this pure awareness and
he talks about this you know kind of
like this transition from the zero point
field to the unify field and and there's
an amazing teacher of transcendental
meditation that also talks about this
John Hegelan so John Hegelan is a
quantum physicist who is also a
transcendental meditation teacher and he
talks about the same kind of thing so
there's like this you know the big dense
third D you know 3D stuff like a chair
okay and you know Dr. Kinsow uses a
chair. And then underneath that you've
got molecular composition in case of
molecules. Then you've got the atomic.
Then you've got the subatomic. You've
got the particles. You've got like you
know the quantum weight.
And then when all of that's gone, you've
got the zero point field. But adjacent
to the nothing is the everything is the
all. So in Buddhism that's also a
principle
that the empty bowl the zen
if you take everything out including ego
you have the potential for all you know
the vastness of source
to enter.
And so I started to get this and I
started to recognize that that black
hole fear was really just a tunnel to
the everything or a
transition
place. And so it just was really
interesting. So all this had to kind of
occur on a quantum level with me. I
actually created a technique, a
meditation practice based on all this
>> information that I learned from this.
and um and it's called quantum wholeness
meditation. So I actually developed that
then I went to do to so then I went to
to do transcendental meditation and and
there's a teacher here in Salt Lake. He
did mention that there are more
billionaires than to teachers and I
thought isn't that interesting? So it's
a rare thing. there's only one in in
Utah, you know, and and I just felt
really privileged to to have that
experience in real life with with his,
you know, wisdom, learn about the
Mahirishi Mahash. I still am,
>> yeah,
>> very much a fan of that led me to other
solutions. So, definitely an important
piece of my journey. However, I will
share I I stuck with the 20 minutes
twice a day or months, I would say, and
then went back to quantum hallless
meditation
partly because I do better and more
committed to it as a group practice. So,
I'm one of those people that I'm going
to do yoga if I go to yoga class and
there's other people in the room when
somebody guiding me. I do meditation if
I know it's at, you know, Monday at
12:30 and we're studying a course of
miracles and doing, you know, meditation
right
>> with intention together,
>> which is I mean that's like I said,
meditation is one of my favorite things,
too. I always end up talking about it in
some form or some way. And I always say
the same thing to people is you got to
find what makes sense to you at that
time in your life. Like whatever is
going to get you to meditate as often as
you're going to,
>> lean into that 100%. That's so cool that
you had um you had all that experience
with meditation before you stumbled into
TM as well. TM is um
>> yeah, it's I found that I feel like a
lot of the the terminology and the
things that you say around like when you
talk about quantum and these sorts of
things, there's a lot of o um overlap uh
to certain words they use in in TM and
like the Maharishi and you know like
when they talk about like the unified
field and cosmic consciousness and
stuff. I feel like there's a lot of
stuff that Sorry. I feel like there's a
lot of stuff.
>> Maharishi was a quantum physicist. Did
you know that? Yeah. Yes. Yeah. That's
so cool.
>> He was um that you know that whole I
think about that often. I've actually
been on a couple retreats with TM. Um I
I I really like it. I you know there's a
lot of weirdness mixed into it for sure.
There's a lot of stuff that if you're
not really into meditation um from the
outside. I can see there's things that
kind of turn people off about it. But um
there's a lot of gold in there for sure
to mine. I mean there's the conversation
I conversations I've had with some of
these guys who have been meditating for
like you know they did their twice a day
for 50 years and uh you know talking to
them about you know quantum physics and
and consciousness and stuff. It's just
so fascinating and cool. There's there's
a lot of um
>> um you know I would hate for any uh
babies to be thrown out with the
bathwater when it comes to you know
because it is getting older. you know,
the the you know, the Maharishi is is
not as big as it was back in the the
70s. You know, this whole guru that they
followed and stuff. So,
>> but um yeah,
>> found a community on Heavenly Mountain.
So that's um a location in North
Carolina where the Maharishi I think had
a house or a a gathering a group there
and they still are very a very committed
community to TM and
>> practices and so yeah it was amazing to
you know connect this group and and
learn more about you know the principles
around it and you know I met someone who
had been to Maharishi University and was
you know just a huge devoted you know,
to that.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. There there's a lot of coolness to
it. Um there's this guy, if you ever
heard of the podcast Buddha at the Gas
Pump.
>> Yeah. Rick Archer. He he used to be a TM
teacher. He lives in Fairfield, Iowa
still. And so he's still he's not super
involved in it. But um I listen to his
podcast all the time and he he still
keeps like TM mentions in his
conversations often. So
>> um
>> Oh, and I love the research that's come
from it. you know the university
>> like it's the reason that meditation has
you know has the strength in our western
culture I think that it does and you
know especially in you know
researchbased or mindfulness type you
know MBSR and is it yeah mindfulness
based stress reduction you know it's
kind of the same model is 20 minutes
twice a day and you know and so people
have adapted I think but it has become a
huge part of are even academic models
that support real solutions I think in
mental health. So so grateful for it.
>> Yeah, I I I would recommend if anybody
could do the 20 minutes twice a day.
There's been periods in my life where I
followed 20 minutes twice a day really
well and then now you know I get most
days I get my 20 minutes at least once a
day and and if I'm have plenty of time I
get my twice a day but um I think
anybody would benefit from that whether
it's a mantra or just mindfulness or
whatever meditation works best for them.
>> You might motivate get back to that.
Thank you.
>> Hey, give it a try. You don't you don't
forget your mantra. Um,
it is this loving thing. I feel like it
is this, you know, it's just this
personal word that doesn't mean anything
to anybody but you, you know,
apparently. So, it is this thing that
throughout the day if I think of my
mantra, I go, "Ah, that's nice." You
know, it is a a resting place within to
some degree.
>> Um,
>> yeah. Well, hey. Um, so what I where I
wanted to go with this, Christine, um, I
think that you would you would speak
elegantly on something that I I often
bring up on this podcast, and it's
identity. Um, I I find identity to be a
big lynch pin to a lot of um, you know,
what ails us and and what heals us in
the different versions of us that are
trying to bloom on the other side of um,
you know, what what's keeping us down,
so to say. So could you based off you
know all the stuff that we've been
talking about and you know the self and
meditation and and um etc all these
things if I was kind of throwing it out
there let's bridge this into a
conversation about identity what comes
up for you what do you think of
>> so big oh
>> I know [laughter]
you didn't really talk a lot about the
quantum body
>> okay
>> but I think we can tie it into that a
little bit so
>> moving from the mental body to quantum
body I think what the The core shift or
element that allows for the healing to
take place is mastery over the ego. So
the ego is not really the identity. If
we were to use that, it would be
lowercase I. And I don't know if you're
do you have any background with the
course of miracles? Have you done any?
>> Uh yeah, I it's on the shelf. I know I
know it a little bit. Yeah,
>> good deal. So that's where I've actually
found the most um support for my own
journey.
>> And it's really a deeper dive into
understanding
um identity, I guess you could say, with
a capital I or self with a capital S.
And so that is the the spirit infused
self. Um the quantum self we could say
would be that higher self that we can
trust and lean into which has more
sourced ent identity you could say with
you know capital I because it is in a
higher frequency you know than we are
and and so I think that is something
I've continued to work on. Um, I did, I
think, go into the psychology fields
because I recognized
there were some core issues with me that
I did not know how to fix. And, you
know, when I delved into personality
disorders, I definitely studied that
deeply. Um, trying to understand myself
and flaws and that type of thing. So, I
have gone I' I've taken that and I've
gone somewhere with that. It's it's
interesting. They're really there's not
a lot in mental health and psychology to
solve personality disorders and those
include things like narcissism, but
there's a lot out there about, you know,
are you, you know, narcissistic abuse,
you know, I just keep seeing that pop up
and I'm like, I kind of cringe.
>> It's the most It's a Buzzfeed word these
days. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's really, it's buzzy and it's
not solutionoriented. So what I find is
it pulls up the victim which is also an
identity, right? And and so that that
victim mindset or it's really an ego
structure is just as big of an issue as
narcissism. You know, it's just not
talked about as much. Um there is
definitely structures around borderline
personality disorder and that's so tough
that you know you bring that up in in
the field of mental health and you know
you watch the therapist turn and be like
oh I'm fold you know I have a waiting
list
um and because it's not there's not
really a solution and the problem is
because there's not really a spiritual
solution in the mental health field and
so so that's what I've discovered is
when you go to that quantum you're solve
olving at a spiritual level and and it's
it's so it's transformative in a way
that
only source can really solve. So, you
know, part of my transformation is I had
a spiritual awakening and that's what
woke me up from a drug induced
lifestyle,
but it also woke up a true identity and
and I started a path of recovery toward
that. Um, my daughter and I have a lot
of deep talks about my 18-year-old about
personality disorders. It's not
something that, you know, every but I
kind of found like she's attracted a lot
of friends who already been diagnosed or
who, you know, know that their dad's
narcissist or, you know, whatever. And
and I've actually influenced the
psychology of, you know, some of this
new generation. I I got to speak to her
psychology class even and talk about
this. And you know, ego structure is
something that I think needs to be part
of the education even of of people
because you're going to run into it.
You're going to deal with it. And and it
doesn't help. And this is one of the
things she was, you know, coming home to
say, "Mom, um, our teachers are saying
this about this." And, you know, my
friend whose father's a narcissist and
hears a teacher say like, "Oh, well,
this is, you know, incurable." You know,
you know, it's not helping,
>> right? So, so understanding that there
is a solution. It just doesn't look like
a pill. It doesn't look like talk
therapy, but it looks like a spiritual
transformation.
That's the answer.
>> And so, I mean, is there this I know
this is a complicated question. Is there
a way to intentionally induce it? That's
not I mean, I know we have psychedelics.
There's things like ibagane treatments
and things like these that are more and
more popular. I I whatever's happening
in that world. Um, people are having
good effects with these, but if people
are just, you know, maybe listening and
maybe they're noticing, hey, these are
things that sound familiar to me. I want
to get started on my journey. Um, you
know, what is maybe a direction that
they can go? You know, I'll have the
links to all of your work down below. Of
course, they can explore more of your
work for sure. You have a lot of great
stuff on your YouTube channel.
Definitely head there. Um, but what
what's something maybe they could try if
if they're listening and this sounds
like right up their alley or similar to
>> So I do have something called the
quantum solutions master class
>> and I include an ego structure component
to that. So it like walks people through
if they want to go deep dive in it. I
talk through all the cluster B, cluster
C personality disorders and talk about
what a spiritual solution looks like
>> and and it's amazing for people that are
in a field of you know mental health or
really I mean like my daughter is going
into probably psychiatric nursing or
something like that she's looking at but
um but really she's using it for life
you know it's like she can now
understand like why she has this
conflict with this person and what how
to frame that in a better way and Yeah.
So,
it's deep dice stuff.
>> Yeah.
>> But I think your listeners are ready for
it.
>> Oh, no. Definitely they are. Um yeah, if
if you're listening to this, you're
you're down to explore some of some of
uh some of all of this stuff really. So,
uh that would be down below. We are
getting up here in time. Um I do I kind
of want to end it with one thing I had.
I was just kind of glancing at my notes.
Uh there's so many things I I could talk
to you for so for so long, Christina. I
feel like um you just doing some
exploratory work on um you on other
podcasts and you on your YouTube channel
and um you on your website just kind of
what you've covered before there's so
much cool stuff. So everybody if
anything of the any of this has
intrigued you explore more of Christine
but um where I want to send us off with
is um chronic pain. You've kind of
briefly mentioned this. If someone is
coming to you to try to think of like
why would the spiritual approach or why
would the um kind of quantum approach be
useful for quantum or sorry not quantum
but a chronic pain.
>> Yeah. What what are our relations with
this chronic pain? Throwing that over to
you.
>> So um so pain is tricky. I I didn't get
into this but um you asked a question
that made me think of the pain body and
so I want to clarify like doctor or is
it no just ehart tole I guess is what he
goes by so echarttole talks about the
pain body and it was during this time
that I was trying to understand my ego
um that I was also studying you know I
was like doing some work with meditation
and you know and course of miracles and
I was also studying at Carti at the time
and I started to realize oh my gosh this
pain body
is a separate separate
call it entity from myself
>> I can separate myself from it and you
know I actually had some tools at my
disposal that helped me do that so
there's you know some of it is related
to poor bodies um definitely finding a
solution outside of narcotics
is a key and that can be mind over
matter. You know, some what we learn
about mindfulness and power meditation
can be part of that. You know, being uh
a simple solution would be notice where
you're not in pain, not where you are in
pain.
Tune into even if it's your hair. Isn't
that funny that
>> I I don't know anybody whose hair is
painted.
>> I love that actually. That's a good one.
>> And it could be the tip of your nose or
your earlo, right? So, it's just
somewhere I know there's somewhere, you
know, even with people with fibromyalgia
that are just feeling it all over the
body. Their hair doesn't hurt to
>> the tip of their nose probably doesn't
hurt and their earlo ear earlo is
probably painfree. So, you just I mean,
you kind of move around into those
pain-free
um aspects of yourself and you can
meditate on that, you know, or use those
as anchors when you're meditating.
and and teach yourself where you want
your focus to be.
>> Yeah.
>> I I think that's genuinely useful. As
you were saying that stuff, I was kind
of just visualizing it a little bit too.
Kind of letting my conscious experience
going to those places that
>> Yeah.
>> you know, just like you know, your hair
hair and whatnot. I think that's
actually a useful thing to spend some
time meditating on. Go to the places
that are not in pain right now.
>> Yeah, that's great. Um
>> and then love. So back to this, you
know, the the essence of endorphins,
that's really on a quantum level what
people are looking for. And in the
endorphin experience is love. And it's a
L capital capital L O V E which can be
infused light you know and
and I know there's stories of people
that they can have that like you talk
about that moment of enlightenment or
that like you know awakening moment and
it could just be
being wrapped in the arms of love.
>> Amen to all that.
That's wonderful. I think that's a great
place to end it. Um, thank you so much
for your time. I I really appreciate
this. Thank you so much for um exploring
this with me and kind of going down some
of these pathways that we went down
today. Um, I'm sure everybody who is
listening is going to come away with
something positive from this. Um, of
course, I'll drop down some links below.
They'll be able to find you and explore
more of your work down below. anything
that you want to mention to sign us off
here um that maybe is not down below or
a special link that they should go down
to below.
>> Well, I'm trying to just get all that
good stuff on my website in a way that
people can explore it, you know, and so
Christinehole.com. If you're listening,
it's no h and Christine, c r i s t i ne
h l. And I'll try to have all this good
stuff for people easy to find as well.
Cool. Love it. Well, thanks thanks one
more everybody. Uh listen listen listen
listen to more Christine. Um check out
more of her stuff. Read more of her
books and love yourself. Drink some
water. Stretch if you have not stretched
today. I mean come on man. You got to
get your stretching on. And we will see
you next episode. Thanks for tuning in
to the Junkair Love podcast.
[music]
Knowledge is power. [music]
Reality is
Junkyard Love podcast.